<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources.atom"/>
  <title>BagsInBulk.ca - Resources</title>
  <updated>2021-08-10T12:05:37-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>BagsInBulk.ca</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/providing-house-socks-for-those-with-no-homes-an-unaddressed-and-serious-need-for-socks-nationwide</id>
    <published>2021-08-10T12:05:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-16T12:40:04-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/providing-house-socks-for-those-with-no-homes-an-unaddressed-and-serious-need-for-socks-nationwide"/>
    <title>Providing House Socks for Those with No Homes – An Unaddressed and Serious Need for Socks Nationwide</title>
    <author>
      <name>Blue Switch</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>A Surprising Gift</strong></p>
<p>Most people don’t think of socks when discussing great gift ideas, but thankfully that’s because most people don’t desperately need them. Some do.</p>
<p>For the countless homeless and displaced persons nationwide who have next to nothing, a gift of a few pairs of socks can feel like the best present they’ve ever received.</p>
<p>Socks are seasonless, soft, comfortable, and for those who are on their feet every day as they move from place to place, they are a crucially important health and hygiene item valued above all others.</p>
<p>Interestingly, socks are often the number one most requested item by shelters and charitable organizations around the country, and that’s why Bags in Bulk has you (and your feet) covered.  BagsinBulk is one of the leading <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-mens-cotton-ankle-socks" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Men's Cotton Ankle Socks" rel="noopener noreferrer">wholesale socks</a> suppliers Canada has. Choose from unbeatable assortments of high quality cotton socks including <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-mens-cotton-crew-socks" target="_blank" title="bulk mens socks" rel="noopener noreferrer">bulk men’s socks</a> and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-womens-cotton-crew-socks" target="_blank" title="bulk womens socks" rel="noopener noreferrer">bulk women’s socks</a> in solid color packs and styles including tube, crew, and ankle socks.</p>
<p><strong>Why Are Socks So Important?</strong></p>
<p>Up to an amazing 35,000 people are homeless on <strong>any given night</strong> according to Statistique Canada. That is not only a staggering statistic, but also a significant portion of the population in desperate need of clean, protective socks for comfort, health, and well-being.</p>
<p>Socks protect feet –especially those without shoes—from rough terrain with sharp rocks and broken glass, provide padding while walking, can prevent frostbite, offer a layer of insulating warmth on cold winter nights, and help wick away moisture and sweat in the summer. They are also perfect for every-day activities including work and school, athletic endeavors, and even just for relaxation.</p>
<p>There are actually a surprisingly large number of individuals and groups that a simple gift of <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-womens-ankle-socks" target="_blank" title="socks in bulk" rel="noopener noreferrer">socks in bulk</a> can truly benefit. Many doctors, nurses, and medical resident students will work shifts the rest of us can’t imagine, sometimes up to 72 hours at a time on call with no chance to go home. Donating a pack of socks to hospitals can benefit both the many patients in need of warm socks, as well as the nurses, doctors, and other exhausted medical staff in need of clean socks to change into during excessively long hours on their feet caring for others. Through the act of donating and showing them that the work they do is both appreciated and noticed, they are provided with a gift any medical staff member would be truly touched by.</p>
<p>Boarding school and university students, as well as active military members, are also always in need of socks. Toss a <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-mens-cotton-ankle-socks" target="_blank" title="socks in bulk" rel="noopener noreferrer">pack of socks</a> into a care package for your student that’s living away from home, and let them share with the rest of their dormitory and their new friends. Nothing beats a care package from home and free stuff when you’re a broke university student. This same sentiment is doubly true for our beloved military members.</p>
<p>Those in our armed forces give so much to their country, and giving back to them even in small ways can mean the world to them. A lone soldier who doesn’t have family to support them, a soldier who may not receive care packages often, or just a surprise given to a local base serves the men and women who are stationed there with a practical, thoughtful, and extremely useful gift they will appreciate for months to come.</p>
<p><strong>Walking a Mile in Another’s Socks</strong></p>
<p>Bags in Bulk offers an unbeatable assortment of men’s socks and women’s socks, both available in ankle and crew cut styles and in various sizes and color packs so that there is always something for everyone.  Donating a pack of highly-needed socks in bulk to homeless shelters, disaster relief centers, or other charitable causes has a wide-reaching and truly powerful impact.</p>
<p>It’s a major “feat” to improve the lives of others, and now it’s easier than ever. Together we can do our part right here at home to make an impactful difference in our communities.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/wonderful-for-weddings-classy-for-classrooms-blanket-bundles-offer-endless-options</id>
    <published>2021-05-25T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/wonderful-for-weddings-classy-for-classrooms-blanket-bundles-offer-endless-options"/>
    <title>Wonderful for Weddings, Classy for Classrooms: Blanket Bundles Offer Endless Options</title>
    <author>
      <name>Blue Switch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A fleece blanket is the perfect gift for any celebration, from weddings to graduations and more! Bags in Bulk offers wholesale blankets in bulk so you can stock up on gifts for all of your upcoming events.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/wonderful-for-weddings-classy-for-classrooms-blanket-bundles-offer-endless-options">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>A Cause for Celebration</strong></p>
<p>Weddings, holidays, and graduations are all momentously happy occasions that – let’s face it – can also be incredibly stressful! They all center around celebrations and the giving of gifts, and everyone knows how challenging some people are to shop for. Thankfully, there’s a gift that’s perfect for everybody.</p>
<p><strong>Blanket Your Loved Ones in Comfort</strong></p>
<p>When it comes to purchasing gifts for friends and family, rarely is there a gift that is needed, practical, and always appreciated. The gift of a soft, warm blanket is the exception to that rule. Bags in Bulk is currently offering a dozen different, unique <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-fleece-blankets-50-x-60-8-assorted-colors" target="_blank" title='Wholesale Fleece Blankets 50" x 60"' rel="noopener noreferrer">24 packs of wholesale fleece blankets</a> in a wide assortment of colors, sizes, and patterns so that there is something for absolutely everybody. There are blankets in solid colors, a 4-color assortment of plaid fleece blankets, two different mixed color packs, as well as 30” x 40”, 50” x 60”, and even 60” x 90” inch throw blanket packs for every reason and season.</p>
<p><strong>Options and Occasions</strong></p>
<p>Weddings are a particularly delightful occasion whereby a pack of <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-plaid-fleece-blankets-50-x-60-assorted-colors" target="_blank" title='Wholesale Plaid Fleece Blankets 50" x 60" ' rel="noopener noreferrer">blankets in bulk</a> comes in particularly handy! For older guests, chilly chapels, and just as a souvenir of the couple’s happy day, an assortment of blankets “to have and to hold, in case guests get cold” are always thoughtful, tasteful, and appreciated by all involved.</p>
<p>Grade school classrooms and high school seniors also find blankets to be particularly thoughtful and useful! In kindergarten and elementary school, nap time blankets in bright colors and soft, snuggly fabrics are perfect for little ones. For a class of graduating high school seniors, distributing a pack of <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-fleece-blankets-50-x-60-8-assorted-colors" target="_blank" title='Wholesale Fleece Blankets 50" x 60"' rel="noopener noreferrer">wholesale fleece blankets</a> that can easily be personalized with names and graduation years is a great way to give each senior something uniquely special to carry with them into the future for use in dorms, at home, and more. </p>
<p>During the holiday season, the gift of soft throw blankets is ideal for older family members, toddlers who would love a soft security blanket to snuggle with, and relatives who are otherwise difficult to shop for! Choose from different style packs (like blue for Hanukkah, or green and red plaids for Christmas, for instance,) different sizes, and even mixed color packs for families where everyone has a very strong opinion on their favorite <em>everything</em>.</p>
<p>Even animal shelters benefit greatly from the gift of a pack of soothing <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-plaid-fleece-blankets-50-x-60-assorted-colors" target="_blank" title='Wholesale Plaid Fleece Blankets 50" x 60" ' rel="noopener noreferrer">blankets in bulk</a>! There are always furry little ones who need a soft, warm, safe space to sleep and snuggle into every night. Blankets help them feel less afraid and more secure in scary cages and crates while they wait for their fur-ever home. A security blanket is the perfect way to help comfort and support the pets there now, as well as those that come next after each one there now has finally found their family.</p>
<p><strong>Seasonless Gifts for Everyone</strong></p>
<p>Giving the gift of a pack of wholesale fleece blankets benefits every recipient both now and well into the future. Blankets are a gift that reflects kindness and thoughtfulness, and which are practical, fun, different, and will be both appreciated as well as actually used, time and again. Best of all, all of our fleece blankets are crafted from 100% hypoallergenic microfiber fleece, which means that children, adults, and pets alike can enjoy their new snuggleable blankets without worry!</p>
<p>Throw blankets are the gift that gives back in immeasurable ways. What are you waiting for? Grab a pack of fleece blankets today for family, friends, holidays, sleepovers, camping, donation, and so much more, and never miss a moment of comfort.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/blanketing-those-in-need-with-the-gift-of-strength-love-and-comfort</id>
    <published>2021-05-24T14:01:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-24T14:01:49-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/blanketing-those-in-need-with-the-gift-of-strength-love-and-comfort"/>
    <title>Blanketing Those in Need with the Gift of Strength, Love, and Comfort</title>
    <author>
      <name>Blue Switch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>A throw blanket is a basic amenity for most people, but can make a huge difference in the life of homeless and displaced persons nationwide. Bags in Bulk offers wholesale fleece blankets in a variety of colors and patterns that can easily be donated to shelters, providing a feeling of comfort and safety to those in need.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/blanketing-those-in-need-with-the-gift-of-strength-love-and-comfort">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>The Security of a Throw Blanket</strong></p>
<p>No matter the weather or season, when someone returns home after a long day it is always a wonderful feeling to curl up under a nice throw blanket to relax and read, watch tv, or just drift off to sleep. It’s such a basic amenity that most people tend to take it entirely for granted.</p>
<p>For the thousands of homeless and displaced persons nationwide, however, the basic comfort and warmth of a blanket is something that many can only long for. They sleep on hard, wet cardboard and jagged pavement, often with little to no protection against the elements or even people passing by.</p>
<p><strong>We’ve Got You “Covered”</strong></p>
<p>Comfort and a soft sleeping blanket are two basic rights that we at Bags in Bulk believe all human beings deserve access to. We offer a dozen different, unique <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-fleece-blankets-50-x-60-8-assorted-colors" target="_blank" title='Wholesale Fleece Blankets 50" x 60"' rel="noopener noreferrer">24 packs of bulk fleece blankets</a> in a wide assortment of colors, sizes, and patterns so that there is something for every need and every community. There are blankets in solid colors, wholesale <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-plaid-fleece-blankets-50-x-60-assorted-colors" target="_blank" title='Wholesale Plaid Fleece Blankets 50" x 60"' rel="noopener noreferrer">plaid fleece blankets</a> in sets of 4 color-styles, two different mixed color packs, as well as 30” x 40”, 50” x 60”, and even 60” x 90” inch throw blanket packs for every reason and season.</p>
<p><strong>A Blanketed Approach to Helping Others</strong></p>
<p>Donating blankets to a homeless shelter, women’s center, or even a nursing home provides comfort and a feeling of care (and warmth) to those individuals most in need of it.</p>
<p>Most importantly, though, is the fact that the gift of a donation of <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-blankets/products/wholesale-fleece-blankets-50-x-60-8-assorted-colors" target="_blank" title='Wholesale Fleece Blankets 50" x 60"' rel="noopener noreferrer">bulk fleece blankets</a> provides so much more than just the physical gift of a blanket. A blanket is a universal symbol for security and love. To be enveloped in a donated blanket is to know that someone cares, that an individual is not alone, and that they have protection against the elements, the roughness of the streets, and even feelings of loneliness. It gives a bed cover to an individual without one, an extra layer of warmth on cold nights, a soft place to lie down, and a way to feel safe.  </p>
<p>A gifted blanket signifies hope, and there is no greater gift than that.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/giving-back-with-backpacks</id>
    <published>2021-05-10T13:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-11T10:26:33-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/giving-back-with-backpacks"/>
    <title>Giving Back with Backpacks; A Simple Gift with A Powerful Impact</title>
    <author>
      <name>Blue Switch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Bags in Bulk is proud to be one of our nation’s premier affordable, quality wholesale backpacks in bulk providers. With an extensive collection of every size, color, and every feature and function of backpack, there’s something for every need, every age, and every community.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/giving-back-with-backpacks">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>What Would You Do</strong><br>If you had to pack up your life and take only your most important possessions with you, what would you take? If you knew you could never return and could only bring that which you could carry, you would likely take some <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-hygiene-kits/products/wholesale-classic-15-piece-hygiene-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Classic 15 Piece Hygiene Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">hygiene supplies</a>, clothes, a pair of shoes, a cellphone, and perhaps some trinkets or photos that meant a lot to you. For homeless, displaced, and individuals who are victims of domestic abuse and natural disasters, this is a stark reality. To make matters worse, often for safety or reasons of other immediate need, some individuals are forced to flee their homes with only the clothes on their backs, and any charitable supplies they are given later they are forced to either hand-carry with them, or simply refuse because they have no way of traveling with these items.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In these tragic scenarios, it makes an already unfortunate situation that much worse, and that much harder to get out of. But it doesn’t have to be that way! The simple gift of a <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-15-inch-promo-backpack-5-color-assortment" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 15 Inch Promo Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer">backpack</a> can help individuals receive the supplies they need in a manner that’s easy to carry, can help them organize and keep clean and safe that which they already have, and can show those who have often lost it all that there is still hope, and still those who care about them and their wellbeing.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Smart Features Save Lives</strong></p>
<p>Bags in Bulk is proud to be one of our nation’s premier affordable, quality <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-15-inch-backpack" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 15 Inch Promo Backpack " rel="noopener noreferrer">wholesale backpacks</a> in bulk providers. With an extensive collection of every size, color, and every feature and function of backpack, there’s something for every need, every age, and every community.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Our <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-trailmaker-19-inch-multi-pocket-backpack-girls" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Trailmaker 19 Inch Multi Pocket Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer">multi-pocket</a>, dual compartment, reflective, clip, and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-trailmaker-seventeen-inch-bungee-backpack-with-side-pocket" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Trailmaker 17 Inch Bungee Backpack With Side Pocket" rel="noopener noreferrer">bungee</a> backpacks in bulk are especially useful to displaced populations. Multiple pocket and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-trailmaker-double-compartment-backpack-with-padding-assorted-girl-colors" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Trailmaker Double Compartment Backpack with Padding" rel="noopener noreferrer">compartment backpacks</a> offer numerous ways to store and organize a person’s most important and cherished items so that nothing gets broken or left behind, while a <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-19-inch-quilted-backpack-with-carabiner-clip-laptop-sleeve" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 19 Inch Quilted Backpack With Carabiner Clip" rel="noopener noreferrer">clip</a> or bungee backpack offers an individual the ability to clip or secure important items such as coats to the front of their bags for easy access and travel. Features like this are especially important to individuals who must move from place to place and shelter to shelter. Reflective backpacks are extremely important as well. For individuals who make their homes outside in busy cities and towns, being seen at night by cars and passersby is critical to staying safe, being noticed, and avoiding accidents with vehicles and bicycles.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>What You Can Do</strong><br>The need and use for bulk backpacks is endless. All it takes is a kind donor to help a community or shelter that’s struggling to ensure that those who depend most on its services have all they need to succeed and get back on their feet.</p>
<p> </p>
<span>Don’t pack a bag and run away from a need that so easily can be met. Let’s work together to do our part and ensure that everyone has access to this most basic of supplies, and can back-pack their way to success and better circumstances.</span>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/one-stop-shop-for-school-supply-kits</id>
    <published>2021-05-05T14:10:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-11T11:22:34-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/one-stop-shop-for-school-supply-kits"/>
    <title>Tools for Schools: A One Stop Shop for School Supply Kits</title>
    <author>
      <name>Blue Switch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Here at Bags in Bulk there’s definitely a way to help! We are the premier supplier of both bulk school supplies </span><em>and<span> </span></em><span>wholesale school supply kits, at unbeatable prices. With just one click you can ship any teacher’s wish list of items directly to their classroom or the homes of their students, and make back to school season a lot less stressful.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/one-stop-shop-for-school-supply-kits">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Teachers Are Our Greatest Resource</strong><br><br>“Teacher, I need another pencil.” “There aren’t enough rulers for all of us.” “We only have one red crayon left and Maya is using it!” How often do teachers hear these comments from their students, only to realize with dismay that unless they pay for <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-12-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 12 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">school supplies</a> out of their own pockets, there’s nothing they can do to help?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>All teachers have lists of items they desperately need but, due to school budget cuts and strained resources, they can ill-afford to purchase for their classrooms. They need help, and they need it urgently. Teachers, classrooms, and districts nationwide need assistance with stocking the most basic of student items, such as <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-plastic-12-inch-ruler" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Plastic 12 Inch Rulers" rel="noopener noreferrer">rulers</a>, crayons, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-5-pack-of-pencils" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 5 Pack Of Pencils" rel="noopener noreferrer">pencils</a>, glue sticks, folders, and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/products/wholesale-5-inch-scissor-blunt-tip" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 5 Inch Scissor Blunt Tip" rel="noopener noreferrer">scissors</a>. Simply put, teachers, our most valued resources for education and student support are, in many ways, completely out of resources.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>What Can Be Done?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Where there’s a will, there’s a way, and here at Bags in bulk there’s definitely a way to help! We are the premier supplier of both bulk school supplies<span> </span><em>and<span> </span></em><a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-twelve-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 20 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">wholesale school supply kits</a>, at unbeatable prices. With just one click you can ship any teacher’s wish list of items directly to their classroom or the homes of their students, and make back to school season a lot less stressful. We offer a wide assortment of bulk rulers, scissors, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-pencil-pouches-1" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Pencil Pouches" rel="noopener noreferrer">pencil cases</a>, pencils, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-ten-pack-of-pens" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 10 Pack of Pens" rel="noopener noreferrer">pens</a>, glue sticks, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/bulk-10-pack-of-crayons" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 10 Pack Of Crayons" rel="noopener noreferrer">crayons</a>, notebooks, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-two-pocket-folders-96-pack" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Two Pocket Folders" rel="noopener noreferrer">folders</a>, and other essential items students of all ages need to meet the requirements of any grade and tackle any challenge.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In some school districts, teachers and students may also require specific essentials that students need for both school<span> </span><em>and</em><span> </span>home. It’s not always possible for a teacher to supply a student with the essentials he or she will need once they leave their classrooms for the day, or when there is homework to complete. That’s why we are thrilled to now be able to offer 12-, 18-, 20-, 30-, and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-twenty-four-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 45 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">45-piece wholesale school supply kits </a>that contain the items all students need to be fully stocked for a year of learning, challenges, and academic advancement both in school and at home. There are even backpack and school supply kits pre-assembled in vibrant colors and sizes, which help ensure that all kids have absolutely everything they need to have a productive year, as well as a convenient and safe way to carry it all.</p>
<p><strong>A Little Help Goes a Long Way</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Every student has the right to a challenging education, but not every school or teacher can afford the tools necessary to provide one. With the simple donation of a pack of school essentials, parents, teachers, and entire school districts can better teach and guide the students in their care. It may not seem like much, but a gift of rulers or scissors can dramatically help fund after school craft programs, woodworking classes, math classes, art classes, and so much more. Pocket folders keep students and teachers on track, paper clips and staplers always keep students’ and teacher’s papers neat and organized, and we all know there is always a need for pencils.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> The impact one simple item can make is immeasurable, but so is the gratitude felt by districts in need when supplies are donated. Let’s work together to make sure every school, every student, and every teacher has the tools they need to succeed.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/back-to-school-supplies-in-bulk</id>
    <published>2021-04-29T23:59:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-11T11:29:05-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/back-to-school-supplies-in-bulk"/>
    <title>Back to School Supplies in Bulk; Maximize a Student’s Potential with a Simple Gift</title>
    <author>
      <name>Blue Switch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Bags In Bulk has the largest variety of quality, durable wholesale school bags and school supplies in bulk nationwide, and at absolutely unbeatable prices. With the click of a button, back to school supplies can be sent to classrooms around the nation, and students everywhere can be fully supplied with every item they need.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/back-to-school-supplies-in-bulk">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><strong>School Essentials are Essential</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Though today’s students have access to technology and tools we could only dream about, some of the most basic essentials of a student’s journey have remained the same. Kids still need <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-1-subject-notebook-wide-ruled-70-sheets" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 1 Subject Notebook" rel="noopener noreferrer">notebooks</a>, rulers, pencils, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-ten-pack-of-pens" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 10 Pack of Pens" rel="noopener noreferrer">pens</a>, scissors, crayons, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-three-pack-of-glue-sticks-forty-eight-cases" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Glue Stick" rel="noopener noreferrer">glue sticks</a>, folders, markers, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-trailmaker-classic-17-inch-backpack-12-color-assortment" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Trailmaker Classic 17 Inch Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer">backpacks</a>, and other related school supplies that help them succeed in their classes, stay organized, complete assignments, and learn by doing.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Unfortunately, not every school district is able to supply every item needed by every student, and in these instances hardships fall on parents that in some cases can, and in some cases cannot, supply their children with the items they most need to succeed. As a result, the academic gap is widening for some under-privileged students and districts, and some students could end up falling behind. Thankfully, it’s not too late to help, and helping has never been easier.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Help Students, Parents, and Teachers<br><br></strong></p>
<p>Bags in bulk has the largest variety of quality, durable <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-solid-color-block-17-inch-backpack-4-colors" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Solid Color Block 17 Inch Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer">wholesale school bags</a> and school supplies in bulk nationwide, and at absolutely unbeatable prices. With the click of a button, back to <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-twelve-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 20 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">school supplies</a> can be sent to classrooms around the nation, and students everywhere can be fully supplied with every item they need. Best of all, there are even the options of purchasing entire school supply kits in bulk! Choose from 12-, 18-, 20-, 30-, and 45-piece school supply supplies in bulk packs, which each include every student’s must-have items such as notebooks, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-two-pocket-folders-96-pack" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Two Pocket Folders" rel="noopener noreferrer">folders</a>, scissors, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-plastic-12-inch-ruler" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Plastic 12 Inch Rulers" rel="noopener noreferrer">rulers</a>, erasers, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-highlighters-pack-of-3" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Highlighters Pack of 3" rel="noopener noreferrer">highlighters</a>, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>What has been a struggle for parents and school districts for ages no longer needs to be. Parents, teachers, and students no longer even need to scour multiple stores to find the best deals on all the items their students need for the school year, because we have assembled absolutely everything into one easy to search and purchase location. There is absolutely no reason that every student in every district nationwide should go without any of the basic items he or she needs to reach their full potential and maximize their learning experience.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Small Acts of Kindness Make Large Impacts</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>A simple purchase of <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-twenty-four-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 45 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">school supplies in bulk</a>, when donated to a school or community in need, can make the difference between having after school programs available to keep kids safe and cared for, or having nothing for students and young people to turn to. A classroom with shared, limited, and sometimes even broken supplies can finally once more also have fresh, new, and up-to-date items that teachers and students need to get the most out of every lesson.</p>
<p> </p>
<span>Most of all, both students and parents will no longer have to worry about feeling the shame of just not being able to afford the most basic of items needed to succeed or expected by their school. Students won’t have to fall behind, teachers won’t have to feel the sting of needing to buy an often endless list of missing supplies, and future generations will receive the proper education, training, and attention that all children deserve.</span>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/wholesale-backpack-attack</id>
    <published>2021-04-09T16:40:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-11T11:43:13-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/wholesale-backpack-attack"/>
    <title>Wholesale Backpack Attack! The Best Selection and Lowest Prices Nationwide Have Arrived</title>
    <author>
      <name>Blue Switch</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>The top-of-the-line, strongest, most unique, and longest-lasting cheap backpacks (in price but never quality) are here.  There’s a backpack, bookbag, knapsack, rucksack, or daybag for every taste and need, every age and grade, and every school requirement!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/wholesale-backpack-attack">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><strong>There’s Something for Everyone</strong></p>
<p>What is fun, brightly colorful, functional, durable, and perfect for all ages? No, this isn’t a knock-knock joke; it’s our back to school sale! The top-of-the-line, strongest, most unique, and longest-lasting <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-15-inch-promo-backpack-5-color-assortment" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 15 Inch Promo Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer">cheap backpacks</a> (in price but never quality) are here.  There’s a backpack, bookbag, knapsack, rucksack, or daybag for every taste and need, every age and grade, and every school requirement! No student should ever have to go without this most basic of <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-12-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 12 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">back to school essentials</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Unique Colors and Characters</strong></p>
<p>Here at Bags in bulk we believe that a<a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-17-inch-printed-backpacks-boys-3-color" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 17 Inch Printed Backpacks" rel="noopener noreferrer"> child’s backpack</a> should be as fun-loving and full of imagination as the child who wears it. This is why our extensive collection of wholesale backpacks include exciting <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-17-inch-printed-backpacks-girls" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 17 Inch Printed Backpacks" rel="noopener noreferrer">bright color patterns</a> and an amusing assortment of magical creatures and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-15-inch-character-backpacks-girls-boys-assortment" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 15 Inch Character Backpacks" rel="noopener noreferrer">characters</a> which dance, fly, frolic, play, and pounce across every kids’ backpack.</p>
<p>Every child has a favorite animal (real or imaginary), a picturesque scene that makes them happy, or a hobby that they want to show off to their friends and teachers. Now, they can, every day, at school. Our wholesale backpack collections offer everything from velvet flowers and polka dots to sunny rainbows, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-17-inch-printed-backpacks" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 17 Inch Printed Backpacks" rel="noopener noreferrer">dancing dinosaurs, majestic unicorns</a>, partying llamas, snarky sharks, and even alien spaceships complete with astronaut abductions.</p>
<p><strong><br>School Compliance and Safety Features</strong></p>
<p>Perhaps even more importantly than how cute and playful these backpacks are, is the fact that there is also a huge assortment of school security-compliant backpacks that come with amazing safety features!</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-trailmaker-classic-17-inch-clear-backpack-5-color-assortment" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Trailmaker Classic 17 Inch Clear Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer">clear backpacks</a> offer pop color trim that is appealing to all kids, and makes mandatory clear backpack requirements fun and fresh, while still staying within full school compliance guidelines. Our<a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-trailmaker-17-inch-mesh-backpack-girls-assortment" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Trailmaker 17 Inch Mesh Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer"> mesh backpacks</a> for boys and girls are perfectly transparent but offer full compartment access to books, folders, and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-1-subject-notebook-wide-ruled-70-sheets" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 1 Subject Notebook - Wide Ruled" rel="noopener noreferrer">notebooks</a>, front pockets for accessories, and come in every color in the rainbow (plus some extras!) A few select styles are even equipped with a reflective front patch that helps every wearer be seen in any lighting.</p>
<p>There are also collections of colorful, <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-backpacks/products/wholesale-trailmaker-classic-17-inch-backpack-12-color-assortment" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Trailmaker Classic 17 Inch Backpack" rel="noopener noreferrer">solid 17 inch backpacks</a> with full front reflective stripes and side pockets, neon color backpacks that stand out and offer the ease of visibility, and even purple laptop backpacks that offer visibility, unique style, and the ability for any student to bring their necessary electronics to and from classes, fully protected.</p>
<p><strong>Let’s Help Every Student Have a Productive Year</strong></p>
<p>We here at Bags in bulk are committed to offering the best in quality, cheap backpacks nationwide so that every organization, every school, and every student can access the bag they need to carry their homework, essentials, electronics, gym clothes, and after school items everywhere they need, all year long. Every student needs a backpack, and every backpack assortment donated offers a student the chance to reach their full academic potential. Together, we can supply every child in every district with everything they need to succeed this year and beyond.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/test-taking-bulk-school-supplies</id>
    <published>2019-02-27T12:13:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T11:50:36-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/test-taking-bulk-school-supplies"/>
    <title>Make Test Taking More Exciting with Bulk School Supplies</title>
    <author>
      <name>bagsinbulk Admin</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>It doesn’t take a rigorous physiological study to learn that test taking isn’t a student’s favorite part of school. Perhaps they may enjoy certain lessons or subjects, but the thought of having to memorize hours’ worth of information can make some feel anxious or disheartened from school. Luckily teachers have the power of school supply kits on their side to make test taking a more approachable and exciting task for students to overcome. We’ve come up with a few tricks to help teachers encourage students to not only do well on test but be excited to take them as well.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/test-taking-bulk-school-supplies">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It doesn’t take a rigorous physiological study to learn that test taking isn’t a student’s favorite part of school. Perhaps they may enjoy certain lessons or subjects, but the thought of having to memorize hours’ worth of information can make some feel anxious or disheartened from school. Luckily teachers have the power of <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-12-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 12 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">school supply kits</a> on their side to make test taking a more approachable and exciting task for students to overcome. We’ve come up with a few tricks to help teachers encourage students to not only do well on test but be excited to take them as well.</span></p>
<h2><b>Decorated Test Dividers</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most intimidating part of a test for a child is the lack of a support system. For weeks you’re there to correct their mistakes and act as a trampoline when they get a wrong answer, but a test challenges their independent thought without you there to nudge them along. A simple way to make students more comfortable and exciting while test taking is to add a familiar element to the process, such as decorated test dividers. Many teachers opt to pass around</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">two folders</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and have students stand them up on their desks in order to keep them from peeking at others answers. Spend a lesson allowing your students to decorate their personal test dividers to get them excited for test taking and becoming familiar with the process. And instead of breaking the bank, order <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-two-pocket-folders-96-pack" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Two Pocket Folders" rel="noopener noreferrer">folders in bulk</a> from our <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-twelve-piece-school-supply-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 20 Piece School Supply Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">wholesale school supply kits</a> to ensure you have enough for every student.</span></p>
<h2><b>Index Flash Cards</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second thing that may be nagging at students when it comes to taking a test is lack of preparation. While you cannot personally ensure that each child goes home to study, you can</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/blogs/resources/how-to-positively-reinforce-your-child-with-new-school-supplies"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">positively reinforce</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> them to do prepare during their free time. Distributing</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-pack-of-100-index-cards" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Pack of 100 Index Cards" rel="noopener noreferrer"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">bulk index cards</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for students to create flashcards is a great motivator. Offer extra credit to those who study with their flashcards to encourage more students to complete the task. Allow them to get creative and offer extra points to students who color code or include clever pneumonic devices or fun graphics to their cards. Students will likely be more excited for test taking when they are confident in the material. Incentivizing students to create flashcards out of bulk index cards will help their studies immensely.</span></p>
<h2><b>Fun Tests  </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes it doesn’t matter how much a student studies, they’re still anxious to get the test over with. In that case perhaps it’s time to rethink the way we administer tests. There are certain rules we seem to take for granted, like the seriousness we treat exams with. Maybe it’s time to break the test taking ice and make them a little more fun for our students and subsequently, our teachers. Allow students to get creative with their answers. For example, if you’re asking students to identify the element neon, hand out</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=colored%20pencils"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">bulk colored pencils</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for them to draw a visual representation. Another way to make test taking more exciting is to add an oral section to the test in which you can talk one on one with students to ascertain their knowledge.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a teacher it’s part of your job to push students to succeed. Showing them ways in which test taking can be exciting is a skill they’ll take with them through higher education. And at </span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bags in Bulk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> we want to assure every teacher that showing your students the value of school doesn’t have to cost an arm and a leg with our affordable school supply kits. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/promote-team-spirit</id>
    <published>2019-02-18T12:21:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T15:40:23-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/promote-team-spirit"/>
    <title>Promoting Team Spirit with Bags in Bulk</title>
    <author>
      <name>bagsinbulk Admin</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;">At</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/"><span> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bags in Bulk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we want to give the best for our customers and financing the apparel for a team of 20 or 30 is no simple task. Therefore, we pride ourselves on providing the lowest prices for<span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale backpacks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>and more, so you don’t break the bank while raising your team’s spirit.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/promote-team-spirit">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Promoting team spirit is a great way to get people involved and excited for sports. You want to raise your team’s spirits by showing them you believe in their talent and ability to succeed. One way of showing your support and boosting their morale is to distinguish the team with personal </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale backpacks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or even wholesale socks. At</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Bags in Bulk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we want to give the best for our customers and financing the apparel for a team of 20 or 30 is no simple task. Therefore, we pride ourselves on providing the lowest prices for </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale backpacks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and more, so you don’t break the bank while raising your team’s spirit.</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Backpacks</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of the draw for investing in</span> <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-backpacks"><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale backpacks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for your team is to make the players feel important and proud to participate. Perhaps when arriving at a game, all prepared with their matching backpacks, they’ll feel like their favorite professional players and be more encouraged to win. You can either have backpacks ordered in your team colors or with your team insignia stitches on the side. Show your players that they’re part of a cohesive group with a backpack for packing up their jersey, shoes, water bottle, and more. They’ll feel more connected and excited to perform game after game knowing that they have team spirit stitched to the side of their personal team backpack.</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Socks and Blankets</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> There’s more to a team uniform that just a jersey and matching backpack. If you want to take your team spirit to the next level by investing in</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-personal-care?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=socks"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale socks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-personal-care?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=blankets"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">blankets</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Socks are an enormous part of team culture. From soccer, tennis, baseball, and more, socks denote who you are and who you play for, they distinguish you from the other team. Socks are a fun and simple way to boost team spirit and show that you believe in your team’s individuality. Similarly, blankets are a fun and new way to get your players excited to be part of the team. Any sports player knows that the ride back from games can be cold and long, so adding a comfy fleece blanket to the mix will help players feel more excited about traveling an hour away to compete.</span></p>
<h2><b>Bulk Hygiene Kits</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes sports games may take teams out of state for a night or two. Some might look at this as a team-wide sleepover (this is where the nifty backpack come in handy), but for others it means forgetting vitals items such as toothbrushes, shampoo, deodorant, etc. At Bags in Bulk we offer a</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-personal-care?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=hygiene%20kits"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">bulk hygiene kit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fully prepared with everything you might need when away. Our </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">bulk hygiene kit</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> includes everything from mouthwash to body lotion to ensure that your bus isn’t stinky after a long game. Your players will feel better about themselves and even more so, will always be prepared to take on the opposing team no matter how far the travel is. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/classroom-hygiene-keep-students-healthy</id>
    <published>2019-02-12T12:18:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T11:59:23-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/classroom-hygiene-keep-students-healthy"/>
    <title>Classroom Hygiene Tips to Keep Your Students Healthy</title>
    <author>
      <name>bagsinbulk Admin</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>From avoiding sniffly noses to week long absences, it’s important to educate students on the importance of both classroom hygiene and personal hygiene as well. By helping them form healthy habits now with investments in products like bulk hygiene kits, you’ll not only greatly reduce the likelihood of them getting sick, but you’ll be giving them important tools to ensure their health in the future.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/classroom-hygiene-keep-students-healthy">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Putting 20 to 30 children into a confined space for hours on end can sometimes spell disaster for classroom hygiene, especially during flu season. Classroom hours serve as the perfect breeding ground for both students and teachers to contract nasty stomach bugs, lice, or the common cold. From avoiding sniffly noses to week long absences, it’s important to educate students on the importance of both classroom hygiene and personal hygiene as well. By helping them form healthy habits now with investments in products like <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-hygiene-kits/products/wholesale-classic-15-piece-hygiene-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Classic 15 Piece Hygiene Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">bulk hygiene kits</a>, you’ll not only greatly reduce the likelihood of them getting sick, but you’ll be giving them important tools to ensure their health in the future. </span></p>
<h2><b>Bulk Hygiene Kits</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first step toward great classroom hygiene is to make it highly personal and exciting. Small bottles of hand sanitizer can be costly for teachers, but at Bags in Bulk we offer affordable <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-hygiene-kits/products/wholesale-deluxe-feminine-20-piece-hygiene-kit" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Deluxe Feminine 20 Piece Hygiene Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer">bulk hygiene kits</a>, so each student can partake in the fun while also learning the valuable skill of keeping your hands clean. Have them decorate their individual bottles and keep them on their desks or in their cubbies. After coming in from recess, or before &amp; after lunch, have your students clean their hands to ensure no one passes along germs from one to the other. </span></p>
<h2><b>Classroom Cleaning Tasks</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This one may seem strange. Why would you ask students to sweep the corners of the room to clear dust, or wipe down the staplers or sharpers? Once put in a classroom setting anything to break up lessons, like cleaning, become exciting. Delegate different cleaning tasks to students on a weekly basis so that they help keep the classroom clean while learning to maintain a healthy environment. Some of these tasks may include sweeping, decluttering certain areas of the room, or using wipes to sanitize communal objects such a <a href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/collections/wholesale-school-supplies/products/wholesale-5-inch-scissor-blunt-tip" target="_blank" title="Wholesale 5 Inch Scissor Blunt Tip" rel="noopener noreferrer">scissors</a>, sharpeners, etc.</span></p>
<h2><b>Sending Students to the Nurse</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It might strike you as counterproductive to send students out of class during a lesson, but if you suspect that a student may be contracting a cold, it’s best to send them to the nurse before the germ can spread. Stopping students from seeing the nurse and getting the medication they need will only increase the spread of germs until you have more than one sick student on your hands.   </span></p>
<h2><b>Hygiene Education</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the most critical things you can do to maintain classroom hygiene is to teach your students about the important of staying healthy. You can outline things like proper bodily hygiene, good sleeping habits, the benefits of exercise, etc. It may be difficult for young students to visualize germs and their ability to jump from one person to the next but use cartoon visuals or metaphors, so they can understand how to keep themselves healthy inside and outside the classroom. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/study-tips-for-students</id>
    <published>2019-02-06T16:19:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-24T15:58:08-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/study-tips-for-students"/>
    <title>Study Tips for Students</title>
    <author>
      <name>bagsinbulk Admin</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<style type="text/css"><!--
td {border: 1px solid #ccc;}br {mso-data-placement:same-cell;}
--></style><span data-sheets-value='{"1":2,"2":"We’ve detailed below a few ways to help you students study with the help of wholesale school supplies. Whether it be helping them organize notes before-hand, or highlighting key terms and concepts, you students will be in great hands with a few tips and suggestion on studying for school.  "}' data-sheets-userformat='{"2":13187,"3":{"1":0},"4":[null,2,13624051],"10":2,"11":4,"12":0,"15":"Arial","16":10}'>We’ve detailed below a few ways to help you students study with the help of wholesale school supplies. Whether it be helping them organize notes before-hand, or highlighting key terms and concepts, you students will be in great hands with a few tips and suggestion on studying for school. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/study-tips-for-students">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Test taking can be stressful for any student. As a teacher or administrator, you know first-hand how important it is for students to succeed. A little encouragement goes a long way to bolster a student’s confidence when it comes to taking a test or completing a project. Whether it be helping them organize notes before-hand, or highlighting key terms and concepts, you students will be in great hands with a few tips and suggestion on studying for school. We’ve detailed a few ways to help you students study with the help of </span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale school supplies.</span></a></p>
<h2><b>Folders</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=folders"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Folders</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are a wonderful way to ensure that your students are organized and well prepared to begin studying. Succeeding in school doesn’t begin with studying for tests but with learning the importance of organization during the lead up to bigger exams or projects. Give a class on organization and demonstrate to students the correct way to label different folders in order to keep notes and homework in order. This will be a great help before any test. Instead of frantically rushing to find misplaced notes and review sheets, they’ll have everything they need right there in a folder.</span></p>
<h2><b>Highlighters</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While many teachers discourage the use of highlighters,</span><a href="https://www.cos.edu/Library/WritingCenter/Resources/Pages/Benefits-of-Highlighters.aspx"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">many sources</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> outline the advantages of implementing a highlighting structure into your note taking system. Show your students that while highlighters are exciting, they can help underline key terms within a student’s notes. Spend a preparatory class showing students how to color code notes using your supply of</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=highlighters"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale highlighters</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. When it comes time to study your students will waste no time identifying the important topics to review.</span></p>
<h2><b>Study Groups</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encourage your students to break into groups of three or four to review the material before test, or to brainstorm ideas for projects or presentations. Letting your students collaborate will not only reinforce the subject matter, but allows for students to be social while studying. Pass around an interactive review sheet that students can fill out to help them get a firm grasp on the material. You can achieve the perfect balance between socializing and studying by allowing for five-minute intervals between stretches of review for drinks and bathroom breaks.</span></p>
<h2><b>Prepare for the Unprepared</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In their haste to absorb all this material students may forget scrap paper or pencils at home. And while it is crucial to teach students the importance of preparedness, make sure you have a supply of bulk</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=pencils"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">pencils</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=paper"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">paper</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at the reader to ensure that every student has an equal opportunity to succeed in your classroom.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/organized-student</id>
    <published>2019-02-06T11:17:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-27T15:04:06-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/organized-student"/>
    <title>Keeping Your Student Organized</title>
    <author>
      <name>bagsinbulk Admin</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Organization is a skill that must be taught, and every student can benefit from its teaching whether it be in their professional/academic or personal lives. As a teacher, you can use wholesale school supplies to ensure that every one of your students has equal opportunity to learn the skill and importance of organization for the rest of their careers and lives.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/organized-student">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ultimate goal of any academic setting is to prepare students to tackle the real world. While it is crucial that they understand the basics of Math, English, and more, teachers would be remiss if they didn’t prepare their students to be organized individuals. Organization is a skill that must be taught, and every student can benefit from its teaching whether it be in their professional/academic or personal lives. As a teacher, you can use wholesale school supplies to ensure that every one of your students has equal opportunity to learn the skill and importance of organization for the rest of their careers and lives.</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Binders</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buying bulk school supplies is a wonderful way for teachers and administrators to ensure that every student has an equal opportunity for success without breaking the bank. </span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=binders"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Binders</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can sometimes be pricey as large department stores, but buying them in bulk will greatly lessen the overall cost. A binder is a way for students to house all of their material in one organized space. Have them mark different sections with dividers and folders so that notes, home works, and miscellaneous handouts and flyers will all be in the same space.</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Index Cards</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Often times students need the most assistance before tests and projects. <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/blogs/resources/how-to-make-school-exciting-for-your-students" title="Make school more exciting with wholesale school supplies">In our last blog</a> we outlined a few tips on using wholesale school supplies to help students study. Index cards are a fantastic way to get students excited and motivated to study. Write a concept or date on one side and the definition or correlative event on the opposite. Let students organize their notes into different cards to make for more digestible and organized study. This will be a tool they can take with them to college and further into their career as a simple and fun way to reinforce information.</span></p>
<h2><b>Pencil Cases</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have a case for </span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=Pencil%20Cases"><span style="font-weight: 400;">pencil cases!</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Imagine ruffling through the contents of your student’s bags to find wayward glue sticks and pencils floating around at the bottom, or worse, and entire pack of colored pencils without a box. Help students physically organize their backpacks with pencil cases. Let them place all writing utensils and small items such as sharpeners and erasers within the pouch. They’ll be prepared every day with a pencil or pen without having to dig deep into their backpack.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/what-you-can-do-with-extra-school-supplies</id>
    <published>2019-02-06T10:29:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-27T15:04:06-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/what-you-can-do-with-extra-school-supplies"/>
    <title>What You Can Do with Extra School Supplies</title>
    <author>
      <name>bagsinbulk Admin</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;">There can be any numbers of reasons why you find yourself with a surplus amount of extra school supplies, but the real test is how you’ll utilize those notebooks, or plastic folders. At</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=hand%20sanitizers"><span> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bags in Bulk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we understand the need for wholesale<span> </span>school supplies, but we also promote the importance of utilizing the excess when you simply have too much of it!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/what-you-can-do-with-extra-school-supplies">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When school time comes around we may go a little overboard with buying school supplies in lieu of sales on pencils and papers. Conversely, we may have misjudged the amount of wholesale school supplies to order and are now left with ten boxes of unopened crayons laying to waste in your basement. There can be any numbers of reasons why you find yourself with a surplus amount of extra school supplies, but the real test is how you’ll utilize those clip-boards, or plastic folders. At</span><a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=hand%20sanitizers"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Bags in Bulk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we understand the need for wholesale school supply kits, but we also promote the importance of utilizing the excess when you simply have too much of it!</span></p>
<h2><b>Start a School Supply Drive</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you can start taking department store levels of inventory of your extra school supplies, then perhaps you can establish a school supply drive. There are plenty of programs such as schools, religious institutions, camps, etc. which would greatly benefit from the cost breaks of donated school supplies. As</span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/education/teachers-shelling-out-nearly-500-a-year-on-school-supplies-report-finds/2018/05/14/af2affae-57b8-11e8-b656-a5f8c2a9295d_story.html?utm_term=.d773b2233952"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">funding is cut</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> year after year it becomes increasingly imperative for communities to help their teacher and or religious figures to help sustain programing, even if they’re already buying affordable wholesale school supply kits. One way to ensure the supply shelves are stocked is to host a school supply drive. Showing that the extra school supplies is going toward a good cause and advertising a reward for the family who can bring the most notebooks or pencils are wonderful motivators for people to drop of bags of extra school supplies. Hiding in many people’s basements are folder and reams of paper collecting dust when their children left for college. Reignite the spirit of giving by doing some good with your extra school supplies.</span></p>
<h2><b>Keep It!</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This may come as a shock, but there’s a good reason we should remind you not to discard extra school supplies. In the hustle to clean out closets and drawers before summer break we can throw the baby out with the bathwater and discard barely used school supplies. We live in a culture that thrives on new-ness, but a notebook with only two used papers is as good as new. Parents</span><a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/update/how-much-do-families-spend-on-school-supplies/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">spend up to $200</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> per child on school supplies, much of which goes unused during the school year. When it comes time to cleaning out your child’s locker or desk, think twice before throwing away half sharpened pencils or a notebook full of unused pages because they can help you save money in the long run.</span></p>
<h2><b>Extra School Supplies DIY Projects</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even after all is said and done, extra school supplies come in many forms from half used notebooks to pencils will next to no erasers. When you don’t want to throw something out, but your child simply cannot bring them to class anymore, get creative with some</span><a href="https://www.diyncrafts.com/26697/repurpose/20-brilliant-ways-repurpose-school-supplies-summer"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">DIY art projects</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Have your child invite their friends over with semi used extra school supplies and create decorative picture frames, ipad covers, candles, and more! Not only will you have a new piece of art to add to your fridge, but you’ll teach your child the importance of recycling used materials.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/party-favors-with-bags-in-bulk</id>
    <published>2019-02-05T13:36:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T15:20:10-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/party-favors-with-bags-in-bulk"/>
    <title>Party Favors with Bags in Bulk</title>
    <author>
      <name>bagsinbulk Admin</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>We understand that throwing a party is no simple task and having the peace of mind that you can get wholesale products at an affordable price will do wonders to calm your party planning nerves. So, whether you order</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>wholesale backpacks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>or bulk colored pencils, you’ll be able to throw a party that no one will forget!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/party-favors-with-bags-in-bulk">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When throwing parties for our children, we sometimes need to get creative with the way we engage the partygoers, especially when the party is winding down. You want to send off your guests with a great feeling by creating a party favor they’ll love. There are several ways to achieve this but, as always, it comes down to creativity and resourcefulness. We understand that throwing a party is no simple task and having the peace of mind that you can get wholesale products at an affordable price will do wonders to calm your party planning nerves. So, whether you order</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> wholesale backpacks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or bulk colored pencils, you’ll be able to throw a party that no one will forget!</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Backpacks</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When brainstorming party favor ideas, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“wholesale backpacks”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> may not be the first thought that comes to mind, but with a little creativity you’ll start the next party favor trend! You can use backpacks for any numbers of ways. If you end off your party with a pinata, pass around the backpacks to allow children to store their candy. Alternatively, if the party calls for some DIY art projects, have the partygoers carry their creations home in their personal backpack. There are dozens of colors and designs you can choose from to make your party favor bags fun and memorable. For an added touch, have a patch or logo stitched or printed onto the bags to keep the party going, even after all the guests have gone.</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Colored Pencils</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similarly, your mind might not jump to “wholesale colored pencils” or “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale school supplies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">” at all when strategizing your party favor plan of action, but utilizing </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale school supplies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a wonderful way to ensure you’re not breaking the bank while throwing a party. Whether you send guests off with small sketch pads attached with a pack of wholesale colored pencils, or if you melt down crayons for a multicolored candle party favor, guests will appreciate the gesture. And we encourage you to get creative with our selection of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale school supplies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to create a memorable day. For example, have your child write special notes on index cards and attach them to each party favor bag for a touch that is personal and sweet.</span></p>
<h2><b>When all Else Fails</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When all else fails, a party planner can never go wrong by handing out candy as party goers make their way out. You can keep a good taste in their mouth, literally, by sending home baked goods, chocolates, or whatever else fits the occasion. Consider creating a “candy counter” so that children can pick and choose which sweets they put in their bag, for an activity that is exciting and engaging.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-make-school-exciting-for-your-students</id>
    <published>2019-01-15T14:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-24T15:59:27-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-make-school-exciting-for-your-students"/>
    <title>How to Make School Exciting for Students</title>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Shalom</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keeping students entertained in school is certainly not the easiest task. With the allure of technology and cell phones, students are more likely to be focused on their Fortnight stats over anything else. Therefore, it becomes the job of the teacher to create more engaging lesson plans and activities to encourage students to succeed and become interested in school. Here are a few creative ways to use affordable</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> wholesale school supplies</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">to revolutionize your classroom and excite your students once again!</span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-make-school-exciting-for-your-students">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keeping students entertained in school is certainly not the easiest task. With the allure of technology and cell phones, students are more likely to be focused on their Fortnight stats over anything else. Therefore, it becomes the job of the teacher to create more engaging lesson plans and activities to encourage students to succeed and become interested in school. Here are a few creative ways to use affordable</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> bulk school supplies</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">to revolutionize your classroom and excite your students once again!</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Composition Books</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buying </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">bulk school supplies</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">is a wonderful way to ensure you’re purchasing enough supplies for a full classroom without breaking the bank, and <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=composition%20books">composition books</a> are a great example. Perhaps planning a “journal entry a day” initiative. Start by distributing a special notebook to each student, something they can keep in their desks or cubbies. Begin your classes by allowing them to reflect on their night, or to jot down ideas, anxieties, and excitements. Give them a nudge by presenting a prompt, or by allowing them free range to write as they please. This will start off the lesson with a fresh outlook and hopefully a heightened eagerness to learn.</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Highlighters</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we think of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">bulk school supplies</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">perhaps we think of backpacks or notebooks, but even small items such as <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=highlighters">pens or highlighters</a> deserve the chance to be affordable too! Many teachers discourage students from utilizing highlighters during class, but you can go against the grain. Highlighters are a great way to help students organized notes and create pyramid of importance when studying for quizzes and tests. For example, have them highlight names and dates in yellow and concepts and definitions in green. Not only will their notes more closely resemble your lesson plans but highlighters add a pop of color that will help liven up their studies.</span></p>
<h2><b>Wholesale Crayons and Markers</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes the best way you make a lesson exciting is to take a break and add some fun and games to the day, and what better than arts &amp; crafts? The last thing you want when conducting a fun project is to have 30 students competing for the only blue marker in the pack. Some of the most expensive school supplies include markers and crayons, so choose the more affordable option with a selection of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale school supplies</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">such as <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=colored%20pencils">colored pencils and markers</a>. Depending on the age of your students teach them how to identify particular colors or set up separate art stations around your classroom with small and exciting art projects to complete at each.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Livening up your lesson plans is no easy task. While you don’t want to sacrifice crucial teaching time, every teacher must recognize the need for fun within an academic setting. Utilizing opportunities, such as buying affordable </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">bulk school supplies,</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">brings a teacher one step closer to making their classroom more engaging and students more excited to learn.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/child-school-supplies</id>
    <published>2019-01-15T14:38:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T15:36:58-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/child-school-supplies"/>
    <title>How to Positively Reinforce Your Child</title>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Shalom</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Explain to your child where they could use improvement in school, whether it be academic or behavioral. Give them the tools to succeed, like strategies for better note-taking, or getting in touch with a teacher to change seating arrangements. And be sure continue encouraging and cheering your child on, but do so with the added promise of their own pack of new <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=markers">markers</a> or freshly minted <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=Pencil%20Cases">pencil case</a> to boost their spirits when they bring home a shining report card!   </p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/child-school-supplies">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>It can be difficult to discipline children when they misbehave in school. They may push back against authority and ask the ever curious “why?” Why should I have to sit in class? Why should I listen to my teachers? Why should I study for this test? We could explain to them the stepping stones one takes from elementary school to high school and beyond, though it may be too abstract for them to comprehend. We could discipline them more forcefully with punishment and rules, though it may hamper their spirits. Or we could look at things from a different perspective and help our children (or students) build up a healthy understanding of short term and long-term gratification by using positive reinforcement.</p>
<h2>What is Positive Reinforcement?</h2>
<p>We may not recall all the concepts from our freshman psych class, but perhaps this one will stick. Positive reinforcement is defined as “the addition of a <a href="https://www.verywellmind.com/what-is-positive-reinforcement-2795412">reinforcing stimulus</a> following a behavior that makes it more likely that the behavior will occur again in the future.” In other words, it means reinforcing a positive action, say getting a good grade, with a rewarding stimulus, like receiving a new backpack. When practiced correctly, positive enforcement allows a child to learn the value of working toward a goal while fulfilling achieving a task.</p>
<h2>How to Practice Positive Reinforcement with your Children:</h2>
<p>Not every goal should be reinforced with a material reward. If you indulged in a brownie every time you sent an email you’d have a serious problem on your hands. Instead take stock of what your child struggles with. Is it science tests? Completing weekend homework? Identify where your child needs help the most, so you don’t break the bank and they don’t expect a new pack of colored pencils with each spelling test.</p>
<p>Secondly, find what it is you child loves about school. Is it the fresh <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=notebooks">notebooks</a>? Is It <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=highlighters">highlighting</a> notes with seven different neon colors? Nobody knows your child like you do and you’d be at a loss if you didn’t use this knowledge to help them get a leg up on their studies. Some children love a fresh <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=binders">loose-leaf binder</a> to decorate with stickers, others get ecstatic for a new <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-backpacks">backpack</a>. Find what your child loves and use that to spur a new interest in school and studies.</p>
<p>The last step of the process is how you approach the situation. Explain to your child where they could use improvement in school, whether it be academic or behavioral. Give them the tools to succeed, like strategies for better note-taking, or getting in touch with a teacher to change seating arrangements. And be sure continue encouraging and cheering your child on, but do so with the added promise of their own pack of new <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=markers">markers</a> or freshly minted <a href="https://bagsinbulk.com/collections/wholesale-school-supplies?_=pf&amp;pf_t_filter_by_product=Pencil%20Cases">pencil case</a> to boost their spirits when they bring home a shining report card!   </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-help-your-child-become-a-successful-middle-school-student</id>
    <published>2018-08-20T17:11:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-24T16:01:19-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-help-your-child-become-a-successful-middle-school-student"/>
    <title>How to Help Your Child Become a Successful Middle School Student</title>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Shalom</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Many difficulties are sure to arise when students make the transition from elementary school to middle school. It is certainly overwhelming for them to deal with an increased workload, the transition into adolescence, and additional extracurricular activities. Find out how parents can help their children through these tough times.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-help-your-child-become-a-successful-middle-school-student">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>About the Author<br></strong><em>Jane Williamson has a Masters of Education from Northwestern University. She is the founder, instructor, and curriculum writer for a 10-week writing program for elementary school students.</em></p>
<hr>
<p> </p>
<p>Middle school can be a difficult time for children due to a number of factors, including the often rocky transition between youth and adolescence and the demands of the academic workload combined with extracurricular activities such as sports.</p>
<p>The following list of online resources can help parents navigate the waters of middle school, which typically spans from 6th through 8th grade. The guide offers tips and suggestions related to study skills, reading, memory, and test/essay preparation. There is also a helpful list of online resources that focus on parental support.</p>
<h2>Study Skills</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.bkwcsd.k12.ny.us/Guidance/SuccessinMS.cfm">Balancing Work and Fun</a>: A New York school district compiles a list of study tips, including prioritizing school work over socializing.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.byui.edu/academic-support-centers/study-skills/study-skills-courses">Videos on Study Skills</a>: BYU offers short videos to help your student with thinking skills, procrastination, memorization and more.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.greatschools.org/gk/articles/study-skills-for-middle-school-and-beyond/">Study Skills</a>: GreatSchools.org, the country's leading source of information on school performance, offers tips on how to master middle school survival skills.</p>
<p><a href="https://campushealth.unc.edu/health-topics/academic-success/obstacles-academic-success/avoiding-study-traps">Study Traps</a>: The University of North Carolina's guide on how to avoid excuses and get back to the books.</p>
<p><a href="https://scs.tamu.edu/?q=node/90">Self-Help Listening Skills</a>: Suggestions on how to improve the often overlooked communication skill of listening.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ecpi.edu/blog/10-best-study-habits-of-successful-students">10 Best Study Habits</a>: A list of 10 key study habits.</p>
<h2>Reading</h2>
<p><a href="http://writingcenter.fas.harvard.edu/pages/how-do-close-reading">Close Reading</a>: Tips on how to read a text closely. This can be used before writing an essay or independently.</p>
<p><a href="http://education.cu-portland.edu/blog/educator-tips/5-strategies-to-improve-reading-habits-of-middle-schoolers/">Improving Reading Habits</a>: Vocabulary development, parent-modeling, free choice and shared reading suggestions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/test-prep/sat/new-sat-tips-planning/sat-reading-test-strategies/a/sat-active-reading-strategies-part-1-sq3r">Active Reading Strategies</a>: A popular system that strengthens reading muscles and helps you to understand more of what you’re reading as you read it for the first time.</p>
<h2>Memory and Focus</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.helpguide.org/articles/memory/how-to-improve-your-memory.htm">Improving Concentration and Memory</a>: Virginia Tech's Counseling Center offers detailed tips on how to improve memory and concentration.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.apa.org/gradpsych/2011/11/study-smart.aspx">Improve your memory, reading, and study habits</a>: A college study guide that focuses on motivation, study skills, effective reading skills and ways to improve your memory.</p>
<p><a href="http://scs.tamu.edu/?q=node/95">Tools for Memory Enhancement</a>: Tips and tricks to boost your memory and concentration.</p>
<h2>Test and Essay Prep</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.greatschools.org/gk/videos/how-to-help-your-child-ease-test-anxiety/">Ease Test Anxiety</a>: Author Annie Murphy Paul shares techniques on how to ease test anxiety.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.helpguide.org/articles/anxiety/therapy-for-anxiety-disorders.htm">Steps to Overcome Anxiety</a>: A helpful guide to to overcoming anxiety.</p>
<p><a href="http://pbskids.org/itsmylife/school/teststress/article10.html">Ten Terrific Test-Taking Tips</a>: Helpful pointers on how to manage test stress.</p>
<p><a href="http://writingcenter.fas.harvard.edu/pages/essay-structure">Mapping the Essay</a>: Harvard College's strategies for writing an essay.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.butte.edu/departments/cas/tipsheets/studystrategies/essay_tests.html">Essay Test Strategies</a>: A thorough tip sheet that walks the student through the essay exam from prewriting to looking for common keywords.</p>
<h2>Parental Support</h2>
<p><a href="http://kidshealth.org/parent/growth/learning/school-help-middle.html">Parent Support</a>: Parental support can greatly help our preteens navigate middle school, from attending back-to-school night to being aware of disciplinary policies.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.scholastic.com/parents/resources/article/more-school-involvement/success-tips-middle-school-principal">Parental Tips from a Principal</a>: Advice from a middle school principal on how to stay involved while your preteen becomes increasingly independent.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.aap.org/en-us/about-the-aap/aap-press-room/pages/let-them-sleep-aap-recommends-delaying-start-times-of-middle-and-high-schools-to-combat-teen-sleep-deprivation.aspx">Let Them Sleep</a>: The American Academy of Pediatrics says middle school-age students should get 9.5 hours of sleep per night, and anything less can result in a decline in academic performance.</p>
<p><a href="http://learning.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/09/27/what-advice-would-you-give-younger-kids-about-middle-or-high-school/">Advice from Peers</a><span> </span>– An article in which older kids offer advice to incoming middle and high schoolers from The Learning Network at The New York Times.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.edutopia.org/blog/middle-schooler-mind-how-brains-learn-heather-wolpert-gawron">The Mind of a Middle Schooler</a><span> </span>– Understanding the middle school child's brain.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amle.org/BrowsebyTopic/WhatsNew/WNDet.aspx?ArtMID=888&amp;ArticleID=513">College and Career Ready</a>: The Association for Middle Level Education's article on what being college and career ready means for middle school students.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Bags In Bulk is a top provider of<span> </span><a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-backpacks">wholesale backpacks</a><span> </span>for schools and charitable organizations.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/study-tips-for-college-students</id>
    <published>2018-08-19T17:13:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T15:36:22-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/study-tips-for-college-students"/>
    <title>Essential Study Tips for Successful College Students</title>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Shalom</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>The first day of college is quickly approaching and the stress of this new stage of life has settled in. To prepare for the workload that comes with college classes, read this complete list of resources for college students.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/study-tips-for-college-students">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>About the Author<br></strong><em>Jennifer Biederman has a PhD in Conservation Biology and a Master’s Degree in Education. She has been a full-time university instructor for 8 years and regularly teaches a course that introduces study skills to college students.</em></p>
<hr>
<p> </p>
<p>Bags in Bulk provides charities and schools with <a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-backpacks">wholesale backpacks</a> and <a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-school-supply-kit">wholesale school supply kits</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The transition from high school to college can seem overwhelming - even to the best of students. From packed lecture halls to the new-found freedom of a flexible schedule, life as a college student demands skills related to time management, motivation - and, most importantly - smart study habits.</p>
<p>Below you'll find a complete list of resources to help you build the study skills and lifestyle habits you need to experience success in college.</p>
<h2>Learning To Learn</h2>
<p>The study habits and strategies that were effective in high school may not cut it in college. At first, many new college students find it necessary to spend a bit of time cultivating new skills in order to find success as a college student. From figuring out your learning style to creating the ideal study environment, check out the resources below for expert tips in becoming a better student.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rasmussen.edu/student-life/blogs/college-life/study-environment-tips/">Set the stage</a>: When hitting the books, your surroundings set the stage - and can determine whether or not you have an effective and productive study session. While the ideal study environment varies from student to student, this resource will help you identify the key characteristics of your optimal learning atmosphere.</p>
<p><a href="http://faculty.bucks.edu/specpop/Lrnprfil.htm">Figure out your learning style</a>: When it comes learning, different students have different styles and strengths. Some may prefer to read and write while others benefit most from more applied, hands-on experiences. Determining the style of learning that suits your needs can unlock the secret to successful study strategies. This link provides detailed information about various learning skills, styles, and preferences, along with key tips for identifying your own unique strengths inside the classroom.</p>
<p><a href="https://declara.com/content/35GOAN5R">Assess your skills</a>: Unlike high school, college learning involves a great deal of independence and personal accountability. Without the close student-teacher interaction that's typical of high school, many college students struggle when it comes to finding a study pattern hat works for them. Thankfully, these tips can help you organize an effective way of studying and learning.</p>
<p><a href="http://sarc.sdes.ucf.edu/form-studyskills">Evaluate your study habits</a>: To find success in college level learning, experts have identified six critical study skills: textbook reading, note taking, memory, test preparation, concentration, and time management. Where are you at when it comes to each of these skills? This inventory will help you target your strengths and weaknesses - an essential starting point on the path to becoming a better college student.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dartmouth.edu/~acskills/videos/video_ri.html">Improve reading skills</a>:  Reading proficiency is the foundation of effective studying - and one of the most significant struggles among new college students. This resource from Dartmouth College details the importance of reading comprehension, and offers expert tips for improving reading rate, retention, and comprehension. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.apa.org/monitor/2012/07-08/ce-corner.aspx">Enhance your memory and concentration</a>: The typical college student has a lot to juggle - from social events and activities to exams and group projects. Concentration and memory are two crucial components to successful studying. Mindfulness can enhance concentration, memory, and focus for better overall performance as a college student.</p>
<h2>In The Lecture Hall</h2>
<p>Effective study skills start in the lecture hall. From active listening to taking notes, discover the skills to a successful classroom experience.</p>
<p><a href="http://sas.calpoly.edu/asc/ssl/listening.html">Learning to listen</a>: Did you know that listening is an essential skill for studying and learning? For some students, the art of listening is a skill that can make or break success in the classroom. This link provides an easy mnemonic device for improving listening skills in the lecture hall.</p>
<p><a href="https://lumen.instructure.com/courses/146846/pages/the-importance-of-listening?module_item_id=4320308">The art of active listening</a>: Once you master the art of listening, you can extend this skill into better classroom performance. Take a look at this guide to help you develop or improve your active listening skills while learning key strategies for better note taking and post-lecture reviews.</p>
<p><a href="http://coe.jmu.edu/learningtoolbox/cornellnotes.html">The Cornell method of note taking</a>: When it comes to taking notes, there are many different strategies to choose from. But the Cornell method is hailed as one of the easiest and most effective note taking frameworks, providing a systematic format for synthesizing and organizing your class notes. This link provides a detailed how-to for mastering the Cornell method of note taking for more effective studying and better academic performance.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.csbsju.edu/academic-advising/study-skills-guide/lecture-note-taking">Before-during-after lecture note taking strategy</a>: Taking notes is an activity that isn't restricted to the lecture hall. In fact, experts advise that becoming an effective note taker requires some key steps before, during, and after a lecture. Adopting this comprehensive strategy can result in better studying as well as improved comprehension and retention. Visit this link to learn more.</p>
<h2>Beyond The Books</h2>
<p>When it comes to finding success as a college student, there are a number of factors that can make or break your efforts. In addition to smart study habits, it's also essential to master the art of time management, find time for sleep, and avoid the temptation of procrastination. Below are top resources for going beyond the books to find success in college.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dartmouth.edu/~acskills/success/time.html">Master time management</a>: One of the first challenges faced by many first-time college students is balancing a busy schedule. In addition to classes, the typical college student's calendar will quickly fill with extra-curricular activities including work, clubs, athletic, and social events. Although many college students' schedules are surprisingly flexible, finding time to squeeze in studying takes a smart approach to time management. This link will help new college students master the art of time management to create a well-balanced schedule that leaves plenty of time to hit the books.</p>
<p><a href="https://new.oberlin.edu/office/student-academic-services/make-schedule.dot">Set your schedule</a>:  A daily schedule that follows a consistent pattern of sleeping, eating, exercising, and studying can actually optimize your mental function and physical health. But setting a schedule is a tough task for most college students. This link provides all of the essential tips to help carve out a manageable daily routine that balances sleeping and studying with the more exciting aspects of college life, including socializing and stress-reducing activities that enhance well being. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.campuscalm.com/time_management.html">Stress relieving tips to manage your time</a>: One of the most common complaints among new college students? Too much stress. But don't let feelings of anxiety and pressure distract you from studying or hold you back from achieving the success you know you can achieve. From the importance of getting enough sleep to how essential it is to attend class, this link provides five effective strategies for minimizing stress through better time management and smart daily habits.</p>
<p><a href="http://sas.calpoly.edu/asc/ssl/procrastination.html">Steer clear of procrastination</a>: As your calendar fills with due dates, deadlines, and other demands, it's easy to start putting off projects and study sessions. But staying on top your work is an important part of finding success in college. Whether you feel overwhelmed, or lack the motivation to get things done, it's essential to avoid procrastination at all costs. Here is a detailed link that provides the secrets behind staying ahead of the game while optimizing time management and minimizing stress for a more successful college career.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dartmouth.edu/~acskills/videos/video_sleep.html">The secret power of sleep</a>: When it comes to sleep, college is synonymous with staying up all night. But although late night study sessions and last minute cramming are tempting strategies for staying on top of your work, a lack of sleep can quickly derail your college career and undermine all of your studying efforts. This resource from Dartmouth College explains why sleep is a key ingredient to a successful college career and includes smart tips for squeezing more shut-eye into your busy student schedule.</p>
<h2>General Resources For Smarter Study Skills</h2>
<p><a href="http://centuracollege.edu/blog/10-effective-study-habits-for-college-students/">10 essential study habits</a>: Taking a bit of time to learn the process of studying is a worthwhile investment that can lead to better learning and an enhanced academic performance. This link provides top tips that will prepare you to optimize your college learning experience, including the basic principles behind time management, organization, and prioritization.</p>
<p><a href="http://missioncollege.org/depts/math/resources/">Mastering math</a>: For many college students, math is a difficult subject that consumes a lot of time while causing undue stress. But with a little extra time and attention, you can develop some special study skills that will help you experience success in math. This resource features hints, ideas, and activities for modifying your study skills to achieve greater understanding - and higher scores - in your college level math course.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>From finding much-needed motivation to sidestepping procrastination, effective college study habits demand a suite of skills that aren't always intuitive to the typical college student. With these links, you'll be on the fast-track to developing the skills and habits that will lead to better success in the college classroom.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-start-a-school-supply-drive-for-your-community</id>
    <published>2018-08-18T17:14:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-24T16:05:32-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-start-a-school-supply-drive-for-your-community"/>
    <title>How to Start a School Supply Drive for Your Community</title>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Shalom</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Have you ever thought of organizing a school supply drive for your community? If you have thought about it, you may have wondered where you should start. A school supplies drive may seem a bit overwhelming, but it can be achieved in several different ways. With a few tips and some planning, you can create an impactful event to benefit the youth of your local community,</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/how-to-start-a-school-supply-drive-for-your-community">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>About the Author<br></strong><em>Amanda Swiontek has led several volunteer opportunities to support the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of Central Florida. Amanda’s leadership as a Volunteer Champion for Apple, Inc. helped the organization earn the Heart of Florida United Way Community Volunteer Excellence Award in 2016. She has also facilitated career development and resume writing courses for teen youth at the Boys &amp; Girls Club Tupperware Brands Branch.</em></p>
<hr>
<p> </p>
<p>Bags in Bulk is a leading provider of <a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-backpacks">wholesale backpacks</a> and <a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-tote-bags">wholesale tote bags</a> to charities and schools.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Have you ever thought of organizing a school supply drive for your community? If you have thought about it, you may have wondered where you should start. A school supplies drive may seem a bit overwhelming, but it can be achieved in several different ways. With a few tips and some planning, you can create an impactful event to benefit the youth of your local community.</p>
<h2>Step One: Who Will Benefit?</h2>
<p>Before you start organizing volunteers and planning the event, it is important to set goals. Start by determining the scope of your school supplies drive. First and foremost, you should determine who will benefit from the event. For example, it could be used to gather supplies for:</p>
<ul>
<li>An elementary school</li>
<li>A middle school</li>
<li>A high school</li>
<li>A nonprofit organization</li>
<li>A low-income school</li>
<li>A specific neighborhood or geographic location</li>
<li>A school dedicated to children with accessibility needs</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want to narrow down the drive even further, you can select a specific grade or group within the above categories. In some cases, you may want to set your goal to benefit a group that you have a personal relationship or affiliation with. Another option is to conduct Internet research in order to find local nonprofit organizations partially focused on or dedicated to supporting the youth of your community.</p>
<p>If you decide to support a nonprofit organization, school or other specific community area, contact the organization. You may be able to partner with them before you host your drive. That way, you can speak with a community representative, youth manager or volunteer manager who can help you understand the donation needs for school supplies.</p>
<p>Once you have determined who will benefit from your school drive, you are ready to move to the planning phase.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://bagsinbulk.com/images/gallery/art-1238602_1280.jpg"></p>
<h2>Step Two: What’s Your Plan?</h2>
<p>Now that you know who will benefit from you school supplies drive, you can begin organizing and planning the event. There are several layers to hosting a school supplies drive, so it is best to start planning at a basic level and then go into more detail as you near closer to the event date. Planning and organizing considerations include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Goals for the drive</li>
<li>Location for the drive</li>
<li>Date the drive will be held on</li>
<li>Volunteer needs</li>
<li>School supplies needed</li>
<li>Potential sponsors</li>
</ul>
<p>When deciding on goals, you may want to specify how many children will be assited by the event. If you are working with a school or specific organization, you may be able to collect a list of items needed. For example, instead of just asking for school supplies in general, you can specify the types of items that should be donated. Specific items may include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Backpacks</li>
<li>Pencils</li>
<li>Glue</li>
<li>Crayons</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
<li>Pens</li>
<li>Paper</li>
</ul>
<p>Another school supplies drive strategy is to find a donor to supply large items such as backpacks. The drive can then be used to fill each backpack for a specific child. This strategy is a great fit if the event is scheduled for a specific class or group of children. Donors can purchase backpacks at wholesale rates for as little as $3.</p>
<p>It is important to consider that some people may want to contribute monetary donations for your school supplies drive. To cater to these types of donors, you can set up a list of items allocated for donations. Prices can be set individually or in groups. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>$1.00 buys glue sticks for 20 children</li>
<li>$5 buys paper for 5 children</li>
<li>$20 buys a backpack filled with school supplies for 1 child</li>
<li>$50 buys a 5 pack of pens for 100 children</li>
</ul>
<p>After you have finished organizing and planning for your school supplies drive, your next step is to decide how you will promote your cause.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://bagsinbulk.com/images/gallery/classroom-2093744_1280.jpg"></p>
<h2>Step Three: Promote Your Cause</h2>
<h3>Word of Mouth</h3>
<p>It is important to keep in mind that the school supplies drive is not just about getting people to donate – it is about motivating others to support your cause. How can you motivate others to volunteer, promote and donate? Members of the community must be able to understand and feel connected to the youth selected to benefit from the school supplies drive. To successfully promote the cause, you should be able to explain the need and the impact the event will have on the children. In addition, you should be able to share this information quickly and passionately with your volunteers, partners and potential donors.</p>
<p>One tactic that may help you give others a quick overview of what you are trying to achieve is to formulate an elevator speech. An elevator speech is meant to interest others quickly in your school supplies drive. The speech should be delivered in approximately 20-30 seconds, which is the typical amount of time spent in an elevator with someone else. Your elevator speech should be a brief, persuasive speech that communicates:</p>
<ul>
<li>Who will benefit from the school supplies drive</li>
<li>What school supplies they need</li>
<li>Your goal for the drive</li>
</ul>
<p>If the person you are speaking with shows interest, you can quickly make him or her aware that you are looking for volunteers and/or donors – depending on your current needs. The elevator speech may open the door for a deeper conversation in the moment or it may persuade the listener to discuss the event or the drive goals in more detail at a future time. Before you go into more detail about your school supplies drive, you should determine that the person you are speaking with wants to learn more. After your elevator speech, you can ask for permission to further the conversation with questions such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do you have a couple of minutes for me to tell you more?</li>
<li>Do you have a quick minute to discuss how you can support as a volunteer or donor?</li>
<li>Are you interested in a quick overview of how to be a volunteer?</li>
<li>Would you like some quick info on how you can donate?</li>
</ul>
<p>It is ideal to share the details of your school supplies drive in the moment after giving your elevator speech. However, some people may not have time or prefer to connect later. It is a good practice to be gracious and respectful of the listener's time. If the person you are speaking with indicates they are not interested, you can simply thank them for their time and end the conversation. If the person shows interest in learning more later, follow up questions may include:</p>
<ul>
<li>When is the best time for me to give you a call?</li>
<li>Can I grab your email address so I can send you more information?</li>
<li>Would you like to meet for coffee/lunch in the next week so we can talk?</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="" src="http://bagsinbulk.com/images/gallery/ruler-2099742_1280.jpg"></p>
<h3>Takeaways</h3>
<p>Whether you plan to promote your school supplies drive in person or by leaving information behind, takeaways are an effective way to promote your cause. A takeaway is typically a physical item that someone can keep so they can follow up to participate or to share with others. A takeaway may include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Flyers</li>
<li>Pamphlets</li>
<li>Business Cards</li>
<li>Post cards</li>
</ul>
<p>Takeaways should be brief, but much like your elevator speech, they should quickly inform and persuade others. Some information that should be included:</p>
<ul>
<li>The name of your school supplies drive</li>
<li>Event date</li>
<li>Event location</li>
<li>Event time</li>
<li>Who will benefit from the drive</li>
<li>What supplies or monetary donations will be accepted</li>
<li>Contact phone and email for volunteer interest</li>
<li>Contact phone and email for donation interest</li>
<li>Any deadlines for volunteer interest</li>
<li>Website with more information for the event, school or organization</li>
<li>Sponsors</li>
</ul>
<p>It may be helpful to create a takeaway such as a business card with your contact information and carry it with you. You never know when you will meet someone and strike up a conversation about your school supplies drive. Giving someone a business card specific to your drive is a tangible reminder of the event and potential partnership.</p>
<h3>Digital Information</h3>
<p>In consideration of those who heavily participate in the digital community, it is critical to promote your school supplies drive through electronic resources. You can use several resources to promote your event, which may include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Email</li>
<li>Social media (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, etc.)</li>
<li>Meetup groups (Meetup.com, Eventbrite.com, etc.)</li>
<li>Affiliated organization website</li>
<li>Sponsor website</li>
<li>School website</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are using a flyer or pamphlet to promote your event, these takeaways can easily be transformed into PDF or integrated into a website to provide more information. In addition, you can look for other promotional ways to market your cause.</p>
<p>Driving awareness is key to having a successful school supplies drive. After you decide who will benefit from the school supplies drive, you can plan and focus on promoting your event. With focus and attention to detail, you can host a drive that will have a positive impact on the youth of your community.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Bags In Bulk has recently begun selling <a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-fidget-spinners">wholesale fidget spinners</a> to charities across the country.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/boost-morale-brand-building</id>
    <published>2018-08-17T17:19:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T15:41:03-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/boost-morale-brand-building"/>
    <title>How to Boost Morale with Internal Brand Building</title>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Shalom</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Low morale is an epidemic-level problem in the United States. More than 70 percent of US workers are currently unsatisfied with their jobs...</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://bagsinbulk.ca/blogs/resources/boost-morale-brand-building">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="container">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-9 col-xs-12 col-sm-6">
<div class="row">
<div class="college">
<p>Low morale is an epidemic-level problem in the United States.<span> </span><a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/70-u-s-workers-hate-job-poll-article-1.1381297">More than 70 percent of US workers</a><span> </span>are currently unsatisfied with their jobs.</p>
<p>Why is this the case? As you can imagine, there are many factors at play here. Employees may become demotivated if they face long hours, unfair rules and regulations, unlikable coworkers and bosses, or if they’re facing challenges that are too difficult or too easy. However, one of the most significant influencers of morale is often overlooked—branding and corporate culture.</p>
<p><a href="https://good.co/blog/how-company-culture-can-affect-morale/">More than two-thirds of employees</a><span> </span>believe corporate culture is important for the success of an organization, but most businesses are so worried about the external visibility of their brand (i.e., how clients and customers see it) that they completely neglect its internal visibility (i.e., how their employees see it).</p>
<p>So what can companies do to combat this?</p>
<p><strong>There’s No “Right” Brand</strong></p>
<p>Your company’s identity is wholly unique. There is no such thing as a “right” or “wrong” branding model. However, you’ll need to carefully consider the types of workers you’d like to have, and<span> </span><a href="https://www.elcomcms.com/resources/blog/the-importance-of-culture-and-morale-in-the-workplace">the environment your company offers</a>, when you create or reimagine your branding.</p>
<p>For example, some companies may pride themselves on excellence and professionalism. In these environments, strict dress codes, rigid punctuality, and detail-oriented work will be priorities, and will naturally attract people who fit into that type of environment. Other companies may pride themselves on energy and individuality. In these environments, loose dress codes and creative work will be priorities, and will naturally attract very different types of workers.</p>
<p>To start, you need to identify the key brand characteristics that are most important to your organization (internally). From there, we’ll work on incorporating them in a way that improves employee alignment with that vision.</p>
<p><strong>Best Ways to Improve Internal Branding</strong></p>
<p>By this point, you should have a list of at least a few key brand qualities that you want your employees to be aware of (and hopefully, showcase in their own work). How can you build a culture that encourages the exposure of these qualities?</p>
<ol>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Be consistent.<span> </span></strong>Employees want to have a<span> </span><a href="https://hbr.org/2015/11/how-company-culture-shapes-employee-motivation">sense of purpose and a sense of belonging</a><span> </span>in their workplace. If the goal post keeps moving, or if they receive mixed messages about what the brand represents, they’re going to lose focus and devalue the brand. If you don’t have a solid company culture or internal branding standard in place, this is your time to hash out the details. Create a formal guide on your brand image, voice, and character, and provide those materials to your employees. Make sure everyone knows what your brand is about, and keep those values consistent at all levels.</li>
</ol>
</ol>
<br>
<ol>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Start early.<span> </span></strong>Branding and company culture shouldn’t be something you wedge into an existing workforce (though you may have to if you’re just getting started). Instead, you’ll need to start early in the hiring process—when you’re interviewing candidates. Keep your brand values in mind, and prioritize candidates who showcase those values. Explain, straightforwardly and in detail, what your brand represents, and let your prospective employees choose for themselves whether they’ll fit into that environment. This way, you’ll proactively filter your candidates, and set a high bar for everyone coming in for the first time.</li>
</ol>
</ol>
<br>
<ol>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Liven up the office.<span> </span></strong>Your office layout should speak volumes about your brand. Are you a fun, casual, laid-back place? You should have art on the walls, bright colors, and an open atmosphere. Are you more about individual achievement? You’ll want individual offices, and areas where you can highlight some of your top performers. Immediately upon walking in, your employees and clients should “feel” what type of business you are. If this isn’t the case, it’s time to start redecorating.</li>
</ol>
</ol>
<br>
<ol>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Make your brand visible.<span> </span></strong>You’ll also want to give employees fairly consistent reminders that your brand exists, and what it represents. You don’t have to be overt with this; even subtle suggestions can be effective. For example, you might<span> </span><a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-backpacks">use promotional items</a><span> </span>like backpacks, tote bags, or water bottles that employees can use in their daily lives to advertise your logo and a tagline that emphasizes the most important qualities of your brand.</li>
</ol>
</ol>
<br>
<ol>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Reward compliance.<span> </span></strong>Positive feedback is the best way to encourage behavior; not only does it make employees feel recognized and validated, it makes other employees want to mimic that behavior to earn rewards of their own. Big rewards, like raises and promotions, speak volumes about who you want leading your company, but don’t underestimate the value of small rewards, either. Sometimes, just a pat on the back and a public compliment are enough to see value here.</li>
</ol>
</ol>
<br>
<ol>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Set a standard with leadership.<span> </span></strong>Corporate culture begins with leadership and trickles down to employees. Consciously or unconsciously, staff members follow the standards that their bosses and supervisors set for them; if you instill your brand’s core values in the highest-ranking members of your team, it’s only a matter of time before the entire organization begins to follow them. Hire the right people for these roles.</li>
</ol>
</ol>
<br>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Give feedback and make changes.<span> </span></strong><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/high-octane-women/201210/emotions-are-contagious-choose-your-company-wisely">Emotions are contagious</a>. If you have one negative or chronically stressed employee, they could eventually make your other employees negative or chronically stressed. If they conflict with your brand culture, they could eventually move the entire staff to an entirely different cultural perspective. You need to identify this behavior and correct it before it’s too late; during employee evaluations, make a note of any behaviors that conflict with your brand, and make a plan for how to correct those behaviors. If they continue to persist in a way that doesn’t align with your brand, you may need to look for a replacement. Don’t let a single employee compromise your vision for the brand.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you’re looking for wholesale promotional items you can use to promote your internal brand, check out our<span> </span><a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-backpacks">wholesale backpacks</a><span> </span>and<span> </span><a href="http://bagsinbulk.com/department/wholesale-fidget-spinners">wholesale fidget spinners</a>! We have one of the widest selections and some of the lowest prices you can find online. </p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
